Okay, so you just saw a tour of the areas of AI. And we'll go into these
throughout the course in a little more
depth. But really AI is all around you in a way
that doesn't always categorize so neatly.
In general applied AI is automation of
some kind. There's some kind of decision problem you want to
automate, something that's too hard
for you to do by hand and you want
computer assistance.
So scheduling--airline routing, military
planning--things like that, regularly done
by AI.
Route planning--every time you go get a
traffic map, that's AI.
The search algorithms aren't so different than
the kinds of things we'll do when we study search.
Medical diagnosis.
You can input your symptoms. There are
medical diagnosis systems that will then
try to figure out the underlying
diagnosis. These systems actually in many cases
are very good. There are even cases where
they can be better than humans.
Web search engines. Some of you may have
used a web search engine...
This has got AI everywhere. It's got some natural language in the text,
there's machine learning in figuring out
how to rank results using
multiple kinds of features. It's kind of AI
everywhere in these things.
Spam classifiers: you may have noticed that
the amount of spam you've got your life,
probably,
shot up while you were young,
right, as kind of people learned how to
spam,
and then recently I think it's been
under much better control and that has to do
with a lot better, both machine learning
and AI techniques for spam classification.
Automated help-desks, that's AI.
Fraud detection on your
credit card, product recommendations when
you go to Amazon--all this stuff is AI.
So there are a lot of things
that don't really boil down to
challenging a grandmaster at chess, but are
equally applicable to industry's
problems today, that come from the
techniques that you're gonna learn about
in this course.